Guide to the Les Dames d'Escoffier New York Archive, 1976-2014 MSS.150
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Newsletters
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - LDENY Newsletter: Commemorative Issue, 1973-1993 (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - LDENY, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 161)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 163)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 165)
  - LDENY Newsletter, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 166)
  - Subseries A: LDEI Newsletter
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 167)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 168)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 169)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 173)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - LDEI Newsletter, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Les Amis d'Escoffier Newsletter, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Lettre de la Fondation Auguste d'Escoffier (Newsletter), 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 181)
- Series VII: Administrative Material
  Series VII contains material relevant to the everyday administration of the organization. It contains general information about the organization, the history of the organization, in addition to biographical material about Auguste Escoffier. Subseries A contains the material detailing Les Dames' rules and regulations(by-laws, a constitution, etc.). Subseries B contains material specific to membership in the organization, including membership directories. Subseries C contains material specific to the Les Dames scholarships. Subseries D contains miscellaneous administrative material, such as financial reports, letterheads, and flyers and informational material on organizations with which Les Dames was involved.
  - General Information about LDENY, undated (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - General Information about LDEI, undated (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - History of organization, undated (Box 10, Folder 184)
  - Biographical Material: Auguste Escoffier, undated (Box 10, Folder 185)
  - Subseries A: Rules and Regulations
    - LDENY By-Laws and Constitution, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - LDENY By-Laws, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - LDENY By-Laws, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - LDENY By-Laws, 1995/1997 (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - LDEI By-Laws, 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - LDEI By-Laws, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - LDEI International Policy Book, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 192)
  - Subseries B: Membership
    - LDENY Membership Guide, undated (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - LDENY Rules and Criteria of Membership, undated (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - LDENY Membership Directory, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - LDENY Membership Directory, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - LDENY Membership Directory, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - LDENY Membership Roster, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - LDENY Membership Directory, 1997? (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - LDENY Membership Application Forms, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - LDENY Membership Sponsoring Forms, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - LDENY Obligations of Membership, 1997? (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - LDENY Proposal Packet, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - LDENY Membership (Misc.), undated (Box 11, Folder 204)
    - LDEI Membership Directory, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - Subseries C: Scholarship
    - LDENY Goals, Purpose of Scholarship; Instructions for Applicants, 1977-2000 (Box 11, Folder 206)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 207)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 208)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 209)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 210)
    - LDENY Scholarship (Award Dinner, etc.), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 211)
    - LDENY Scholarship: "Scholar's Reunion", 1988 (Box 11, Folder 212)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - LDENY Scholarship Committee Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - LDENY Scholarship: Award Forms, 1986/1988 (Box 10, Folder 215)
  - Subseries D: Misc. Administrative Material
    - Financial Reports, etc., 1987-1998 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Flyers, mission statements, etc.; from misc. organizations in which LDENY was involved, undated (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - LDENY and LDEI letterhead; writing paper, undated (Box 11, Folder 218)
    - Misc. Material, undated (Box 11, Folder 219)
- Series VIII: Board Meetings
  Series VIII contains minutes, agendas, misc. committee reports, and notes from LDENY board meetings. Subseries A contains the same material, but from LDEI board meetings.
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 220)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 221)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 222)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 223)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 224)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 225)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 226)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 227)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 228)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 229)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 230)
  - LDENY Board Meetings (Jan-July), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 231)
  - LDENY Board Meetings (Aug-Dec), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 232)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 233)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 234)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 235)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 236)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 237)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 238)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 239)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 241)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 242)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 243)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, undated (Box 13, Folder 244)
  - Subseries A: LDEI Board Meetings
    - LDEI Board Meetings, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 245)
    - LDEI Board Meetings: Reports from Local Chapters, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - LDEI Board Meetings, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - LDEI Board Meetings, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - LDEI Board Meetings, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 249)
    - LDEI Board Meetings, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 250)
- Series IX: Binders
  Series IX consists of material originally filed by LDENY members into binders. The material in the binders is primarily administrative (board meetings, etc.),but includes members' correspondence and material relating to Les Dames dinner events.
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Jan-Apr (Box 14, Folder 251)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: May-Aug (Box 14, Folder 252)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Aug-Oct (Box 14, Folder 253)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Oct-Dec (Box 14, Folder 254)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Jan-May, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 255)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: May-July, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 256)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Aug-Nov, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 257)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Nov-Dec, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 258)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Jan-Mar (Box 14, Folder 259)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Apr-May (Box 14, Folder 260)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: June (Box 14, Folder 261)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: June-Aug (Box 14, Folder 262)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Sept-Oct (Box 15, Folder 263)
  - LDENY Binder 1995-1997: Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 264)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Jan-Mar (Box 15, Folder 265)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Apr-May (Box 15, Folder 266)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Annual Dinner (May) (Box 15, Folder 267)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: June-July (Box 15, Folder 268)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Aug-Sept (Box 15, Folder 269)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Oct-Nov (Box 15, Folder 270)
  - LDENY Binder 1998: Dec (Box 15, Folder 271)
  - LDENY 2001 (front sleeve), 1998 (Box 15, Folder 272)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Jan-Feb (Box 16, Folder 273)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Mar-July (Box 16, Folder 274)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Aug-Oct (Box 16, Folder 275)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Nov-Dec (Box 16, Folder 276)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: MFK Fisher Awards (and Misc.) (Box 16, Folder 277)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Member News (and Misc.) (Box 16, Folder 278)
  - LDENY Binder 2001: Grand Dame (and Misc.) (Box 16, Folder 279)
  - LDEI 1995-1996: Jan-May (Box 16, Folder 280)
  - LDEI 1995-1996: June-Dec (Box 16, Folder 281)
  - LDEI 1995-1996: Jan-July (Box 16, Folder 282)
  - LDEI 1995-1996: July-Ooct (Box 16, Folder 283)
  - LDEI 1995-1996 (back sleeve) (Box 16, Folder 284)
- Series X: Publicity
  Series X consists of publicity materials, such as newspaper clippings, press releases, a guest book, as well as photographs, negatives, and slides. The latter largely portray Les Dames scholarship winners and ceremonies, as well as Les Dames dinner events.
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 285)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1980-1983 (Box 17, Folder 286)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1984-1989 (Box 17, Folder 287)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1990-1996 (Box 17, Folder 288)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases: Gastronomy Wk, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 289)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1999-2001 (Box 17, Folder 290)
  - Visitor's Book, undated (Box 17, Folder 291)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Winners, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 292)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Winners, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 293)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Winners, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 294)
  - Photographs: Reunion of Scholarship Winners 1977-1987, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 295)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Ceremonies, 1988? (Box 17, Folder 296)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Award Dinner, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 297)
  - Photographs: Scholarship Award Dinner (CIA), 1990? (Box 17, Folder 298)
  - Photographs: Award Certificates presented to LDENY, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Photographs: Dinner Event (Art What Thou Eat), 1991 (Box 17, Folder 300)
  - Photographs: Dinner Event (Gracie Mansion), 1992 (Box 17, Folder 301)
  - Photographs: James Beard and Carol Brock, undated (Box 17, Folder 302)
  - Photographs: Misc. (Scholarship ceremonies?), undated (Box 17, Folder 303)
  - Photographs: Misc. (Dinner Events), 1988 (Box 17, Folder 304)
  - Photographs: Misc. (Portraits), undated (Box 17, Folder 305)
  - Photographs: Dinner Events 2000-2002 (Box 18)
  - Photographs: Dinner Events (Misc.), undated (Box 19)
  - Photographs: Dinner Events (Misc.), undated (Box 20)
  - Photographs: Dinner Events (Misc.), undated (Box 21)
  - Photographs, Slides and Negatives: Dinner Events (Misc.), undated (Box 22)
- Series XI: Objects/ Artifacts and Media
  Series XII contains a decorated champagne bottle, a linen bib, and three videorecordings documenting LDENY events.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - LDENY Dinner at the Four Seasons, videorecording, June 2, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 150.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    8mm
  - "Organic Food," videorecording, CBS Evening News, CBS TV-Network, March 4, 2000. Made by Video Monitoring Services of America. (Box 24, Folder 150.0002)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    VHS
  - "Hands On: Master Class with LDENY," videorecording, October 27, 1998. Made by Walnut Park Productions. (Box 24, Folder 150.0003)
    Betacam SP
  - Linen Bib, made by Halston from Belgian linen, for Carol Brock, November 4, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 150.0004)
  - "Name Game: Organic Foods/Genetically Modified Foods," videorecording of LDENY Future Food Symposium, aired on CBS Evening News, CBS TV-Network, March 4, 2000. (Box 24, Folder 150.0005)
  - Brut champagne bottle (empty), black with splotches of paint. Label: Brut 1990/ Aurora Millenium 2000, 1990/2000 (Box 24, Folder 150.0006)
    champagne bottle, glass
- Oversize Series I: LDENY Dinner Events
  Contains oversize material from Series I: Dinner Events, and includes dinner menus, flyers and a poster.
  - LDENY Dinner Events: Art What Thou Eat, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 15b)
  - LDENY Dinner Events: A Taste of Hong Kong, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 15c)
  - LDENY Dinner Events, undated (Box 23, Folder 25b)
- Oversize Series II: Annual Gala Dinners
  Contains oversize dinner menus from Series II: Annual Gala Dinners.
  - LDENY Annual Gala Dinners, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 47b)
  - LDENY Annual Gala Dinners, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 49b)
  - LDENY Annual Gala Dinners, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 49c)
- Oversize Series III: Salute to Women in Gastronomy Week, 1994
  - Proclamation from the Mayor of New York in recognition of Salute to Women in Gastronomy Week, 1994 (Folder 2 Left)
- Accretion 2007 - Series I: LDENY Dinner Events, 1978
  - Subseries A: LDENY Dinner Events
    - LDENY Dinner Events: "A Showcase of Women Chefs", 1978 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - LDENY Dinner Events, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - LDENY Dinner Events, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - LDENY Dinner Events: 2006 Induction Dinner (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - LDENY Dinner Events: 2007 Induction Dinner (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - LDENY Dinner Events, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Accretion 2007 - Series V: Correspondence, 1990
  - Gold, Rozanne, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Accretion 2007 - Series VI: Newsletters, 1994
  - LDENY Newsletter, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Subseries A: LDEI Newsletter
    - LDEI Quarterly - Summer 2007 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Accretion 2007 - Series VII: Administrative Material
  - Subseries D: Misc. Administrative Material
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - LDENY Public Relations Committee Meeting, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Accretion 2007 - Series VIII: Board Meetings
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Accretion 2007 - Series IX: Binders
  - LDENY Binder: 2005 Induction Ceremony, Image Index and Files on CD (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Accretion 2008 - Series I: LDENY Dinner Events
  - Subseries A: LDENY Dinner Events
    - LDENY Dinner Events: "A Night with the Best of Spain", 1987 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - LDENY Dinner Events, 1987 - 1988 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Accretion 2008 - Series II: Annual Gala Dinners
  - LDENY Annual Gala Dinner: Rainbow Room, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Accretion 2008 - Series V: Correspondence
  - Washington, 1985 - 1988 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Accretion 2008 - Series VI: Newsletters
  - Les Dames Journal and Other Info, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Accretion 2008 - Series VII: Administrative Material
  - Subseries A: Rules and Regulations
    - LDENY By-Laws and Constitution, 1978 - 1981 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - By-Laws - Revised (Local/International) 1983 - 1984 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Subseries D: Misc. Administrative Material
    - Miscellaneous Administrative Material, 1984 - 1988 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous - Of Interest, 1985 - 1986 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Materials, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Subseries E: Expansion Committee
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee Consitution, 1976 - 1982 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee New Chapters, 1977 - 1982 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee Constitution, 1980 - 1981 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee Forms, 1980 - 1982 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Expansion Committee - New Chapter Information, 1980 - 1983 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee, 1981 - 1988 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Les Dames - Expansion Committee, 1983 - 1985 (Box 26, Folder 17)
- Accretion 2008 - Series VIII: Board Meetings
  - Les Dames Minutes 1976, 1974 - 1976 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "Beginnings" - LDENY Board Meeting, 1976 - 1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Minutes - 1977 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Minutes - 1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Minutes - 1979 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1979 - 1987 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Minutes - 1980 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Minutes - 1981 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Minutes - 1982 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Minutes of LDENY Board Meetings 4/28/83 to 12/13/85, 1983 - 1985 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1984 - 1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Les Dames January 6, 1987 Board Meeting, 1984 - 1987 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Minutes - 1985 - 1986, 1985 - 1987 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Minutes - 1986 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - LDENY Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Les Dames Board Meeting, 1988 - 1989 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Subseries A: LDEI Board Meetings
    - LDEI Board Meeting (The First) - 1 of 2, 1985 - 1986 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - LDEI Board Meeting (The First) - 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Accretion 2016 - Series XII
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist and materials in this series are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  Scope and Content
  The 2016 accretion to the Les Dames d'Escoffier Archive contains documentation relating to the philanthropic, organizational, and social activities of the society. Materials include CDs and floppy disks, membership directories, newsletters and journals, meeting minutes, fundraising event planning materials, and DVD records of the activities of the presidents of the society from 2011-2014.
  - Abbondanza 2007: How to Run a Gala Fundraiser (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Scholarship Events, 2009-2010 (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
  - Scholarship Awards Event Brief (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Directories, 1975-1980 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Mailing List and Members, 1989-2006 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Old LDEI Directories, 1996, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - By-Laws/Standing Rules, 1990-1998 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - LEDI Quarterly and Journal, 1984-2008 (Box 28, Folder 11-13)
  - Annual Meetings, 1976-1989 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Annual Meetings, 1990-1999 (Box 28, Folder 15-16)
  - Annual Meetings and Board Meetings, 2000-2008 (Box 29, Folder 1, Box 28, Folder 17-21)
  - 2009 and 2010, 2009-2010 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - 2011 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - 2012 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - LDNY Records on DVD, 2013-2014 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - 2014 (Box 29, Folder 6)